Finding Aid for Social Justice in Michigan Web Archive
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Social Justice in Michigan Web Archive
2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library.
2014025 Aa 3 [2014034]
Web collection of websites created by various organizations and individuals whose focus is on social justice and equality in the State of Michigan, archived by the Bentley Historical Library using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler beginning in 2010.
17 web sites online; multiple captures
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Websites gathered beginning in 2010 using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service web crawler.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Social justice in Michigan is among Bentley Historical Library's most important topical collections priorities. The topic's priority is based on the Bentley Library's mission as established by the University of Michigan Board of Regents to document "the state, its institutions, and its social, economic, and intellectual development," the historical collecting patterns of the library, and overall collection development priorities in all formats. The process of setting collecting priorities is described by Christine Weideman's "A New Map for Field Work: Impact of Collections Analysis on the Bentley Historical Library" (American Archivist, Winter 1991, Vol. 54 Issue 1, pp. 54-60.) and Judith E. Endelman's "Looking Backward to Plan for the Future: Collection Analysis for Manuscript Repositories." (American Archivist, Summer 1987, Vol. 50 Issue 3, pp. 340-355.)
In selecting web content for permanent preservation, the Bentley Historical Library seeks:
Websites of organizations or individuals whose archives the Library is committed to preserve.
Website that fill gaps in existing collections.
Websites with unique content that documents the work and/or thought process of a person or organization.
Websites that periodically incorporate new content or feature regular updates.
Websites with content that is not likely to be duplicated in an individual or organization's paper records.
As of 2013, the Bentley Library will concentrate efforts on documenting equality in opportunities for Michigan citizens-- employment opportunities, education, public housing and healthcare, socio-economic conditions, and other aspects. In addition to these priorities, the MHC remains open to the consideration of material with great research potential in any area of Michigan's diverse history.
To learn more about the Bentley Historical Library's Web Archives visit http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/index.php.
The Web Archive of Michigan's Social Justice collection contains archived websites created by various organizations and individuals committed to serving social justice in the State of Michigan. The websites have been archived by the Bentley Historical Library, using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler beginning in 2010. Access to all websites archived by the Bentley Historical Library is available at: http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/webarchives/index.php.
Web Archives include websites of, social justice media, organizations, and activists who call the state of Michigan home. The collection is especially strong in documenting organizations that represent ethnic and marginalized communities in Michigan.
The year that appears next to the website title in the contents list indicates the date that the website was first archived. Archived versions of the site from later dates may also be available.
Subjects:
100 Black Men of Greater Detroit.; Affirmations.; American Friends Service Committee. Michigan Criminal Justice Program.; American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee, Michigan.; Arc Michigan.; Black Autonomy Network Community Organization.; Catholic Church--Michigan--Detroit.MichiganDetroit.; Dignity Detroit.; Equality Michigan.; Interfaith Council for Peace and Justice (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Mental Health Association in Michigan.; Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (Detroit, Mich.); Michigan Coalition Against the Death Penalty.; Michigan Equality (Organization); Michigan Pride (Organization); Michigan Roundtable for Diversity & Inclusion.; Paralyzed Veterans of America. Michigan Chapter.; Pinkney, Edward.; Whirlpool Corporation.; African American men--Michigan--Detroit.; African American youth--Michigan--Detroit.; African Americans--Michigan--Benton Harbor.; African Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; Amnesty.; Arab Americans--Civil rights--Michigan.; Barrier-free design--Michigan--Traverse City.; Bisexuals--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Bisexuals--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Catholic gays--Michigan--Detroit.; Children with disabilities--Michigan.; Civil rights--Michigan.; Criminal justice, Administration of--Michigan.; Developmental disabilities--Michigan.; Disability awareness--Michigan--Traverse City.; Disabled veterans--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Environmental justice--Michigan.; Ethnic communities.; Gay rights--Michigan.; Gays--Michigan.; Gays--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Gays--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; GLBT community of Michigan.; Homeless persons--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Newspapers.; Homosexuality--Societies, etc.--Michigan--Ferndale.; Housing policy--Michigan--Religious aspects.; Human rights.; Hunger.; Islamophobia--Michigan.; Lesbians--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Lesbians--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Mental health--Facilities--Michigan.; Mental health services--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Mental retardation--Michigan.; Minorities--Civil rights--Michigan.; Muslims--Civil rights--Michigan.; Paralytics--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Peace--Societies, etc.--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; People with disabilities--Michigan--Traverse City.; People with mental disabilities--Michigan.; Politics and public policy.; Prisoners--Abuse of--Michigan.; Prisoners--Blogs--Michigan.; Prisoners--Medical care--Michigan.; Prisons--Michigan.; Prisons--Overcrowding--Michigan.; Religious tolerance--Michigan.; Same-sex marriage--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Social justice.; Transgender people--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Transgender people--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Transportation and state--Michigan--Religious aspects.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Benton Harbor (Mich.); Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Social life and customs.; Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Economic conditions.; Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Race relations.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Race relations.; Fernadale (Mich.); Traverse City (Mich.); Washtenaw County (Mich.)
Contributors:
Benton Spirit Community Newspaper.; Groundcover News.; Odgers, Susan.
Genre Terms:
Blogs.; Websites.
- Social Justice in Michigan Web Archives
  - 100 Black Men of Detroit, 2011
  - Advocacy for Michigan Prisoners and Their Families, 2012
  - Affirmations, 2010
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee-Michigan, 2010
  - Arc Michigan, 2012
  - Benton Spirit Community Newspaper, 2011
  - Black Autonomy Network Community Organization, 2011
  - Dignity Detroit, 2012
  - Equality Michigan, 2012
  - Groundcover News, 2012
  - Interfaith Council for Peace and Justice, 2012
  - Mental Health Association in Michigan, 2012
  - Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength, 2012
  - Michigan Paralyzed Veterans of America, 2012
  - Michigan Pride, 2012
  - Michigan Roundtable for Diversity & Inclusion, 2011
  - Susan Odgers: Adapted in TC Traverse City Record-Eagle, 2012